<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Publications &#8211; Levene Energy</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>The Innovative Solutions Provider</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 18:40:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Levene-Energy-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Publications &#8211; Levene Energy</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Role Of Energy In Sustainable Development</title>
		<link>./../../../the-role-of-energy-in-sustainable-development/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../the-role-of-energy-in-sustainable-development/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[IT Helpdesk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Publications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings We all have several needs but surely not enough money and resources to meet them all. How do you adequately satisfy the need for food, clothing and shelter for one and ensure that the needs of another, who will be born 40 years after, will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings</strong></p>



<p>We all have several needs but surely not enough money and resources to meet them all. How do you adequately satisfy the need for food, clothing and shelter for one and ensure that the needs of another, who will be born 40 years after, will also be adequately met without one affecting the other? Sustainable development hopes to get this done.</p>



<p>The phrase ‘Sustainable Development’ became an anthem after the United Nations General Assembly in 2015 adopted the Sustainable Development Goals to achieve a better world. Beyond the anthem, sustainable development seeks to ensure a world where human needs are met without disrupting the stability and integrity of our planet.</p>



<p>The UN has listed 17 goals as steps to how it can attain sustainable development. They include zero hunger, no poverty, good health and well-being, quality education, clean water and sanitation, affordable and clean energy, industry, innovation and infrastructure, sustainable cities and communities, responsible production and consumption, and climate action.</p>



<p>However, energy lies at the centre of the climate equation and the quest to build a sustainable world. In fact, the United Nations describes it as the key to solving some of the challenges being experienced.</p>



<p>From heat production to keep us warm to electricity generation to power homes, industries and fuel for vehicles, trains and aeroplanes, energy plays a vital role in human existence. Thus, it cannot be ignored in the quest to build a sustainable world.</p>



<p>Fossil fuels, such as oil &amp; gas and coal, have been identified as the largest contributors to the climate change problem. Data from the UN shows that fossil fuels are responsible for an estimated 90% of all carbon dioxide emissions and about 75% of greenhouse gas emissions.</p>



<p>The effects of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases on the environment can be likened to that of a blanket. It traps heat from the sun and reduces the earth’s ability to cool itself by radiating this heat back into space. This has led to a phenomenon called climate change, where the earth is hotter, and there is increased drought and more severe storms – to mention a few.</p>



<p>To avoid the worst impact of climate change, the UN has set a goal to reduce emissions by almost half in 2030 and achieve zero emissions by 2050. This is the basis for the climate change conversation.</p>



<p>Seeing how crucial the need for energy is for human survival, alternative energy sources are being explored on a daily basis. This research has resulted in electric cars and electricity generation using heat from the sun (solar power), water and wind. The possibility of electricity generation from waste is also being explored.</p>



<p>Several arguments have been made in favour of renewable energy; its sources are all around us, it is cheaper, it creates jobs, it is healthier, and all these mean that it makes economic sense.</p>



<p>To ensure everyone is on the same page, countries have been encouraged to develop an energy mix that does not lean heavily on fossil fuels and cut spending/funding for projects powered by fossil fuels. Large corporations and companies have been encouraged to reduce their carbon footprint and offset emissions by donating to green energy projects and planting trees. Companies in the oil &amp; gas sector (including Levene Energy) are also making moves to shift their focus and spending from crude oil to renewable energy.</p>



<p>However, critics have described the green energy campaign as unfair to developing countries like Nigeria. Their argument is that if coal powered the development and industrialisation of European countries, the United States of America and even the United Kingdom, why should oil-rich countries not enjoy using their resources for their development?</p>



<p>Their argument seems valid when the contribution of African countries to greenhouse gas emissions (estimated to be about 3.8%) is considered, yet these countries also bear the brunt of the effects of climate change.</p>



<p>The initial refusal of China and the European Union to fund a ‘loss-and-damage’ fund for the world’s most vulnerable countries, which also have to contend with the effects of climate change, also gives their stance some fuel.</p>



<p>This incident was one of the highlights of the 27th Conference of Parties – the United Nations climate change conference (COP27) held in Egypt. The EU had said that it would only partake in the fund if China were also a donor, insisting that the Asian powerhouse has developed significantly since it was categorised as a developing nation in the 1990s and has now become one of the biggest greenhouse gas emitters.</p>



<p>Thankfully, the historical ‘loss-and-damage’ fund was set up. The fund will have a broader funding arrangement outside the UN climate change process from other sources such as insurance, donor contribution, oil &amp; gas tax, and debt relief.</p>



<p>Frans Timmermans, the Vice President of the European Commission, has also said the fund should cover middle-income countries like Pakistan.</p>



<p>The road to sustainable development is a long one for the countries of the world. Energy – whether green or otherwise – will play a crucial role in determining what will be left of our planet in another 100 years.</p>



<p>Will it be cool and green with plants flourishing? Or will it be one hot, chaotic planet with oil spills and other industrial waste? Only time will tell.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../the-role-of-energy-in-sustainable-development/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Levene Energy Be Considered A Modern Agent of Sustainable Energy?</title>
		<link>./../../../can-levene-energy-be-considered-a-modern-agent-of-sustainable-energy/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../can-levene-energy-be-considered-a-modern-agent-of-sustainable-energy/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[IT Helpdesk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Publications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings Energy remains a necessity of life, helping people to get by every day. But in recent years, investment and conversations around how energy is generated and consumed have witnessed the most dramatic shift. Yet it remains a moving one. Think of the medieval beginnings when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings</strong></p>



<p>Energy remains a necessity of life, helping people to get by every day. But in recent years, investment and conversations around how energy is generated and consumed have witnessed the most dramatic shift. Yet it remains a moving one. Think of the medieval beginnings when early men had to ignite fire through friction from stones to cook food. From that time on to the discovery of coal and other fossils, which powered the industrial revolution of the 18th century and now renewables, humans have always wanted more from energy. This has led to endless discoveries. Energy innovation after innovation has forced people and businesses to constantly adapt to energy changes that can sometimes be disruptive throughout history, shaping how the world around us evolves.</p>



<p>Fossil fuels like coal and crude oil are not only harmful to the planet, but they are also finite resources compromising the safety of future generations and ecosystems. Hence, the global push towards sustainable energy better known as renewables. This includes energy sources such as wind, solar, hydro and biomass which are readily replaced, viable and cannot be depleted, and which emit little or no greenhouse gases (GHG).</p>



<p>In the Nigerian energy scene, the search for sustainable energy had been long-drawn and often marred by indifference on the part of the government coupled with low private investment. This has led to a lack of access to energy in many parts. Until recently, the Integrated Photo Voltaic (BIPV), is said to be the largest in Africa. BIPVs are products and systems that generate solar power and can be easily integrated into different building parts, including roofs and windows. The project, when completed, will further open up the solar energy space in Nigeria and set the country on the cusp of reaching a new renewable milestone.</p>



<p>As hinted in a recently launched Renewable Energy Roadmap (Remap) by the Nigerian government and the International Renewable Energy Agency, in Nigeria, nearly 60% of the nation’s energy demand by 2050 is projected to be met through renewable energy sources. The global renewable power capacity is expected to grow by 2400 gigawatts (GW) in just five years: between 2022-2027. This is as much as the renewable power added in the last 20 years, according to a recent forecast by the International Energy Agency (IEA). The forecast further indicated that solar and wind sources would be the biggest driver of renewables.</p>



<p>If investments in renewables are aggressive enough, bookmakers are projecting it could drive down costs and give more people access to energy in remote areas, something Levene Energy already has in the pipeline. Following its strategic partnership with NNPC Gas Marketing Limited (NGML) to build and operate gas pipelines, Levene Energy is primed to take advantage of the gas commercialisation policy of the Nigerian government, rapidly evolving as a modern agent of sustainable energy on the African continent.</p>



<p>To harness the abundance of potential that was hitherto untapped in the energy sector as well as achieve Nigeria’s goal of universal access to energy by 2030, government and operators in the energy sector would have to synergise and lead practical initiatives targeted at making more energy companies with the right mix of technologies and private capital key into the nation’s energy sustainability plans. This will fast-track Nigeria’s pursuit of the United Nations&#8217; net-zero emissions plans by 2060 and bolster energy security in a nation of over 200 million people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../can-levene-energy-be-considered-a-modern-agent-of-sustainable-energy/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Nigerian Businesses Can Compete Globally</title>
		<link>./../../../how-nigerian-businesses-can-compete-globally/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../how-nigerian-businesses-can-compete-globally/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[IT Helpdesk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Publications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings As Africa’s largest economy, Nigeria is strategically positioned to be a significant player in the global economy. Given the right support and the fact that the country is potentially fertile ground for massive growth and development, Nigerian businesses can claim the top spot globally. But [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings</strong></p>



<p>As Africa’s largest economy, Nigeria is strategically positioned to be a significant player in the global economy. Given the right support and the fact that the country is potentially fertile ground for massive growth and development, Nigerian businesses can claim the top spot globally. But for this to happen, several issues must be considered.</p>



<p>Entrepreneurship largely depends on the existence, maintenance, and improvement of adequate infrastructure. Given that Nigerian roads, ports, and airports are often in disrepair, it has made logistics a nightmare, and reaching new markets has become a difficult challenge. Additionally, there is the insidious challenge of frequent power outages, which disrupt business operations, making it difficult for businesses to attain optimal performance, and this, in turn, hinders competitiveness for Nigerian businesses, both locally and internationally. It would be easier for a business in a country with already existing basic infrastructure to grapple with other essential issues such as finding customers, recruiting, and retaining staff, expanding to new and foreign markets, etc.</p>



<p>However, when one has to constantly expend most of their capital on buying fuel for backup generators, vehicle repair, costly transportation, and excessive turnovers, one begins to wonder at what cost an average entrepreneur would be able to develop and maintain their customer base as well as reach new markets.</p>



<p>For a country tilting towards industrialization, thanks to the increasing number of manufacturers, production is only sustainable if these infrastructural needs are met. Most of the work to be done in this regard lies with the government and the people of Nigeria, who must adopt a production mindset, contrary to the consumption mentality that existed before this era.</p>



<p>Another crippling issue of competition among SMEs in Nigeria is the lack of access to capital. Many businesses do not have adequate access to capital at reasonable rates, and this limits their ability to grow and compete. As a result of the lack of support from financial institutions, SMEs often struggle to secure needed funding. Nigerian businesses must invest in the latest technology and training to ensure growth and success in today&#8217;s global market. They need funding to make these investments. A quick solution would be for the government to conduct a review and implement existing regulations, the passing of more business-friendly laws, and expressly encouraging more financial institutions to lend to SMEs. Alternatively, businesses can seek other sources of financing, such as crowdfunding and peer-to-peer lending, which have become increasingly popular in recent years.</p>



<p>Yet another significant challenge is corruption. Businesses are often faced with this issue, especially in their first few years, but even older businesses are not exempt from its effects. Corruption is a major obstacle that plays a part in every sector of the country. For SMEs, corruption is a familiar enemy, and the consequences are stunted growth, lack of competition and, ultimately, this leads to the death of innovation. Many businesses are over-taxed by government officials who demand bribes for ‘little favours’. This increases businesses&#8217; difficulties in operating effectively and limits the incentives found in systems where healthy competition is encouraged. Naturally, this leads to a lack of trust in the business community, as well as a loss of confidence in the government. To resolve this, the government, as well as the people, must take a zero-tolerance approach to corruption and work to create a more transparent and trustworthy business environment to attract investors and encourage competition, thereby making it easier for businesses in Nigeria to reach their full potential.</p>



<p>The most basic aspect of entrepreneurship is innovation. This is why SMEs must take steps to become more competitive. Investing in technology and training is a perfect way to improve operations and gain a competitive advantage. Businesses can increase their efficiency and competitiveness by adopting modern technologies such as cloud computing and data analytics because what gets measured gets done. Training and development opportunities must be provided for employees to achieve consistency in this area. Another result that can be achieved by this form of investment is that employees are more likely to be retained, especially those who are talented and whose careers would benefit greatly from these self-development initiatives. Employees generally stay when they feel like they are part of a bigger dream. Companies that invest in their employees and provide them with growth opportunities are more likely to retain talented employees, giving them a competitive advantage.</p>



<p>One other way to enhance the capacity of employees is through mentorship. Businesses can set up mentorship programmed to help employees at all levels, from new hires to executives, with advice and support. By implementing strong mentorship programmes, businesses in Nigeria can tap into the knowledge, experience, and expertise of seasoned professionals and develop the skills and competencies needed to compete on a global stage.</p>



<p>Diversification of products and services is also an excellent way of increasing competitiveness. New markets offer fresh perspectives, challenges and opportunities. Total reliance on a specific product or market could limit the business and its potential for expansion and expose it to economic downturns. If a business can tap into new and growing markets, it can increase its competitive advantage.</p>



<p>For global dominance, Nigerian businesses must look beyond the country’s borders and explore opportunities in other African countries. An opportunity for Nigerian businesses to access a market of over 1.3 billion people and a GDP of over $3 trillion has come to light with Nigeria’s ratification of the African Continental Free Trade Area (AfCFTA) agreement which came into effect in January 2021. Businesses can now take advantage of the growing intra-African trade and expand their customer base. This will not only help them to become more competitive globally but will also contribute to the overall economic development of Africa.</p>



<p>In conclusion, for Nigerian businesses to compete globally, both the Nigerian government and stakeholders in these industries must come together in their numbers to address the issues as stated above. The government must take the lead in addressing infrastructure and corruption issues, while businesses must focus on investing in technology and training (including mentorship), diversifying their products and services, and exploring new markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../how-nigerian-businesses-can-compete-globally/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Energy and Sustainability: How Levene Energy is Bridging the Gap</title>
		<link>./../../../energy-and-sustainability-how-levene-energy-is-bridging-the-gap/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../energy-and-sustainability-how-levene-energy-is-bridging-the-gap/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[IT Helpdesk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Publications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings Over the past three decades, there have been rising concerns about the environmental impact of climate change, as well as the economic implications of burning carbon-based fuels. These concerns have inspired innovation in the field of renewable energy for mass consumption. The Climate Change 2022; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>By: Nzan Ogbe, Group Chief Executive Officer, Levene Energy Holdings</strong></p>



<p>Over the past three decades, there have been rising concerns about the environmental impact of climate change, as well as the economic implications of burning carbon-based fuels. These concerns have inspired innovation in the field of renewable energy for mass consumption. The Climate Change 2022; Impacts, Adaptation and Vulnerability report released by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) reveals that over 40 percent of the global population is being pushed beyond its limits to adapt to climate change. As part of the United Nations&#8217; continued efforts to ensure that global warming doesn&#8217;t exceed the 1.5°C mark, reduction in greenhouse gas emissions was echoed throughout the annual UN meeting on climate, Conference of Parties (COPs), that was held late last year in Egypt, to deliberate on sustainability strategies to mitigate global warming.</p>



<p>With over 200 government representatives, the conference served as a melting pot of strategies for reducing emissions, including helping countries prepare for and deal with climate change and securing technical support and funding for developing countries that lacked supporting infrastructure. To be sure, the cumulative climb in global temperature is solely a human factor contributed by the burning of fossil fuels that, include oil, gas, and coal.</p>



<p>While it makes sense on paper to shun the burning of fossil fuels to lower emissions, it is worth noting the economic impact. The oil and gas sector provides 85% of global energy needs, so a drastic shift might prove counterproductive. For instance, a 2022 report by Reuters elaborated on how the festering Russia-Ukraine war is disrupting the gas supply to the European Union (EU)—clearly demonstrating how economies are hooked on crude oil.</p>



<p>This dependency on crude oil can be elucidated in its contributions to the gross domestic product (GDP) of oil-producing countries, its role in facilitating industrial processes, and its influence on lifestyle. A total removal would only harshly remind the world of its heavy reliance on crude oil, thus posing a dilemma. Through sustainability strategies, the oil and gas industry can better adhere to Health, Safety, and Environmental regulations to positively impact their immediate environment. These strategies buy time to shift to more sustainable energy sources.</p>



<p>By 2030, renewable energy sources will account for 65% of global electricity and could decarbonize 90% of the power sector (Renewable Energy – Powering a Safer Future, a UN report projects). Currently, the oil and gas sector is inching towards investing in energy-efficient solutions.</p>



<p>Since the 1980s, renewable energy projects such as wind and solar have been introduced to lessen fossil fuel reliance methodically, and over time, the technology behind harnessing these renewable energies has improved significantly from the first-generation models that generated meagre energy.</p>



<p>With technological advancements in the development of cheap, renewable energy, more and more oil and gas companies or energy companies are in the process of transitioning from fossil fuel combustion. Nigerian energy solution providers like Levene Energy are at the forefront of building this new frontier.</p>



<p>From inception, Levene Energy has continued to make significant strides in the upstream, midstream, and downstream sectors via a series of group diversification efforts that introduced subsidiaries positioned to offer sustainable energy solutions at all levels of the oil and gas value chain.</p>



<p>Guided by the United Nations Development Programme&#8217;s (UNDP) Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) to attain a low-carbon future through carbon reduction projects, Levene Energy entered into a strategic partnership with a pioneering renewable and sustainable energy company to birth a joint venture enterprise known as LPV Technologies (LPV).</p>



<p>In September 2021, LPV embarked on a historical project of retrofitting a 17-storey building with Building-Integrated Photovoltaics (BIPV), earning it the bragging rights of executing the largest installation of BIPV in Africa.</p>



<p>The solar power generating system composed of 955 KWp BIPV and a 2.0 MWh storage unit produces 1.0 MWp of clean energy that is sufficient for the building&#8217;s daily energy needs, thus decreasing their number of emissions and strain on the power grid.</p>



<p>Climate change is a global emergency, one that requires proactive steps that introduce green energy solutions. But where this isn&#8217;t attainable due to economic restraint or technology, transitioning to low-carbon fuel alternatives is the best bet. Natural gas is a low-carbon fuel juxtaposed with high-content fossil fuels like coal and oil. The adoption of gas will help reduce carbon emissions.</p>



<p>Through another one of its component entities called Aegon Distribution Limited (which is a midstream-focused offshoot), Levene Energy has joined the leading global energy solutions companies in providing the infrastructure needed to transition from diesel to gas. Signing an Unincorporated Joint Venture (UJV) with NNPC Gas Marketing Limited (NGML), it has commenced building and operating gas pipelines to locations where the low carbon fossil is needed.</p>



<p>In other cases, when renewable energy or low-carbon fuel is not an alternative, the entire oil and gas value chain can be optimized, not for the production of greener fuels, but to ensure that technologies help in making better operational choices in the upstream sector, and not to negatively impact the environment.</p>



<p>Traditional Exploration &amp; Production (E&amp;P) methods are crude and contribute significantly to the carbon footprint by emitting gases like methane. Clean technology solutions adopted by She-Val Engineering (another component entity within the Group) promotes the sustainability of other resources, such as decreasing the volume of freshwater used in the extraction of crude oil. This is a significant intervention because Nigeria is the largest oil producer in Africa.</p>



<p>The race to reverse climate change&#8217;s impact, evident in melting ice caps in the northern hemisphere, rising sea levels, food shortage, and extreme weather, is gaining momentum. Many of the set goals will certainly be attained in the coming years through the innovation of tech-forward firms like Levene Energy Group.</p>



<p>By and large, innovative technology will catch up with climate change and stop it in its tracks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../energy-and-sustainability-how-levene-energy-is-bridging-the-gap/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating Value Through Dedication and Ethical Business Operations</title>
		<link>./../../../creating-value-through-dedication-and-ethical-business-operations/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[IT Helpdesk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Publications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Nzan Ogbe, Founder and CEO of Levene Energy Holdings By positioning itself at every stage of the oil and gas value chain and now expanding into solar energy products, Levene Energy Holdings has built its reputation as a leading energy solutions provider. Levene Energy Holdings is a multifaceted, diversified entity specializing in the upstream, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>By: Nzan Ogbe, Founder and CEO of Levene Energy Holdings</strong></h5>



<p>By positioning itself at every stage of the oil and gas value chain and now expanding into solar energy products, Levene Energy Holdings has built its reputation as a leading energy solutions provider.</p>



<p>Levene Energy Holdings is a multifaceted, diversified entity specializing in the upstream, downstream, and midstream spaces of the oil and gas industry. As an innovative solutions provider, Levene leverages advanced technology, highly qualified professionals, and global best practices to create value for its stakeholders. Nzan Ogbe, Founder and pioneer CEO of Levene Energy Holdings, states, “I wanted to prove a point that we could create a Nigerian company that is professional and compliant from a corporate governance standpoint and that we could compete with any company in the world.”</p>



<p>Levene Energy trades with most major international oil companies, extending its operations from Nigeria to Libya and Cameroon. Ogbe states, “We have many collaborations and partnerships with the international oil &amp; gas community, including Shell, BP, Petroineos, to name a few.” In the midstream space, Levene has a gas distribution franchise where the company is in the process of building pipelines to distribute gas to a catchment area in Lagos under a concession arrangement. In the upstream area, Levene has acquired two Bitumen blocks in South-West Nigeria which they are in the process of developing. Levene is also in the advanced stages of acquiring a stake in a Nigerian oil block and also secured four oil blocks in Equatorial Guinea in the bid round of 2019. “The plan was always to own our assets and do a backward integration from exploring and developing our crude and gas assets, refining, and ultimately, selling those refined products to place us at every stage of the entire value chain.”</p>



<p>In addition, Levene recently incorporated a joint venture company called LPV Energies which provides renewable energy solutions, and this is an important aspect of their transition plan. The flagship project for LPV Energies is the Building Integrated Photo-Voltaic (BIPV) project. “The BIPV project is the largest in Europe and Africa. The project has the capacity to generate more than 1MW of electricity which is going to be used to exclusively power the Sterling Bank Towers in Lagos.” There are also projects in the works to generate and distribute solar power in rural areas in Nigeria. Ogbe says, “Renewable energy serves a need. It can reach rural areas and provide electricity for people who have never had it, so it has that social impact as well. For me, this is a very exciting project.”</p>



<p>Levene Energy’s implementation of technology within its operations also reduces costs and increases efficiency. With offices in Abuja, Lagos, London, and Mauritius, technology and remote working have saved both time and money in the company’s daily operations and travel. Ogbe states, “Technology has reduced our costs significantly and aids in our pipeline project. We’re working with a technology provider to ensure that the pipeline is safe and secure, and we receive real-time feedback on everything we do. On the renewable energy side, we&#8217;re in discussions with the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC) where we can deploy our solar panels to their locations to meet the power requirements in these places.”</p>



<p>Not only does Levene make a difference in terms of energy accessibility and affordability, but the company also holds corporate social responsibility close to its heart. Ogbe says, “My son, Aziba, was diagnosed with autism about 15 years ago, and this opened my eyes to the challenges of autism and the level of research that needs to be done and how expensive it is to support a child on the spectrum. We give back to the community through the Zeebah Foundation, where we support funding for research and development to engage with people who have challenges.” Levene also recently contributed to a fund for female children in rural communities who need sponsorship to go to school.</p>



<p>From its impact in the oil and gas industry to renewable energy and even community outreach and CSR initiatives, Levene Energy has made its mark as a company with a reputation that precedes it. Ogbe states, “We value corporate governance, ethical practices, tenacity, innovation, commitment to delivering world-class service and products to our clients.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
